DANNY GALLAGHER

CONTACT

Address: Raleigh NC 27612 **Phone**: (901) 262-1196

Email: danny2549@gmail.com

SKILLS

- MySQL and SQLite
- Excel and VBA
- Python
- Google Adwords and Analytics
- Google Tag Manager
- Keyword Research
- Copy Writing
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Digital Strategy and Digital Auditing
- Search Engine Optimization
- HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript
- Web Scraping using Beautiful Soup

CERTIFICATIONS

- Moz Essentials Certificate
- SEM Rush Mobile Certification
- SEM Rush SEO Fundamentals Certification
- SEM Rush Keyword Research Certification
- SEM Rush Pay Pay Click Certification

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science:

Interdisciplinary Studies, 08/2011 - 08/2016

Mississippi State University - Starkville, MS

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a results-driven SEO specialist with five years of Ecommerce experience. My goal is to increase the visibility of clients and their products through keywords research, meta data manipulation, pay per click marketing through Google AdWords, and digital strategy.

WORK HISTORY

E-commerce SEO Specialist, 05/2019 to Current **Agri Supply** - Garner, NC

- Grew conversion rate on select product pages by 19.6% through keyword research, educational blog post, and regular audience engagement through Google reviews and questions
- Enhanced over 10,000 product listings through product research, adjusting meta descriptions, editing meta titles, and adding alt tags to images
- Created and organized link building strategy while removing harmful back links through the disavow tool

Marketing Consultant, 09/2019 to 03/2019 Pindi House - Memphis. TN

- Set up and optimized Google Merchant Center and Google Search Console
- Worked with graphic designer on all site imagery and edited images for site performance and speed.
- Designed and implemented Instagram marketing strategies
- Performed technical audits to fix site performance using Screaming Frog.

SEO Specialist / Marketing Associate, 09/2016 to 05/2019 **Gant Systems** - Bartlett, TN

- Developed and managed phishing campaign that grew from 2 clients, to 48 clients
- Managed and developed Google Ad Words strategy that steadily grew client's sales by 23.5% each year.
- Tracked, reported, and analyzed and presented in monthly meeting website analytics and PPC initiatives and campaign results.
- Managed and developed email campaigns sent to 2000 customers using Constant Contact

Digital Marketing Associate, 06/2015 to 01/2016 **[K8]** - Remote/Nashville, TN

- Lead in the overall social media marketing strategy
- Monitored client's analytics through Hootsuite and Google Analytics
- Presented data and findings to client in a monthly meeting